Contact

00962788616108 (Mobile) mr.eshtaiwi@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/mreshtaiwi (LinkedIn) mreshtaiwi.github.io/portfolio/ public/ (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Career Development Resume Writing Team Leadership

Shihab Eshtaiwi

Senior Instructor | Career Coaching | [I help Grads get better jobs opportunities by managing their CV's and Linkedin profiles] | Entrepreneurship

Amman, Jordan

Summary

A loving father, innovative, passionate educator who aims to leave a positive imprint everywhere he goes, and an enthusiastic web developer with a growth mindset and passion for sharing knowledge with others

Experienced in motivating others to reach the best of their working levels.

Experience

Abdul Aziz Al Ghurair School of Advanced Computing (ASAC) 3 years 7 months

Senior Instructor March 2023 - Present (2 months) Amman, Jordan

adding to my previous position responsibilities:-

- Helping students build their CVs.
- Prepare students for technical and personal interviews.

Instructor - Coding Program

March 2021 - March 2023 (2 years 1 month)

Amman, Jordan

ASAC is an advanced computing school that helps people to change their lives through career-focused education with an intensive six-month web development coding program powered by Code Fellows partner.

Code Fellows is a technical skills training academy based in Seattle, USA.

Responsibilities:

- Managing and Monitoring students projects (midterm/final).
- Provide weekly/monthly reports.
- Effectively manage and leverage the level of teacher assistants.

- Orchestrate course planning and retrospective meetings.
- Ensure the best possible, highest quality learning environment for students.
- Instruct 101, 102, 201, 301 and 401 courses (giving lectures, writing exams, course planning and grading).
- Instruct according to the guidelines and rules set forth in the Powered By Code Fellows Instructor Handbook.
- Provide training (TOT) for new instructors.
- Alert my supervisor to any significant student issues and provide support as needed.
- Develop and support CF curriculum to improve delivered educational level performance.
- Support other instructors and teacher assistants with the curriculum, as needed.
- Record student performance and report to my supervisors for record-keeping.
- Assist support team in finding, onboarding new instructional staff.

Teacher Assistant

October 2019 - March 2021 (1 year 6 months)

Amman Governorate, Jordan

Assist in helping students understand concepts of software development in order for them to learn in a stack learning environment.

- Debugging student codes, finding errors, and fixing them. [Each student has his/her own way of thinking, the challenge is to adopt their own way of coding and help them in the shortest time.]
- Responsible for grading all assignments within 24 hours of submission in order to keep the Instructor current on student status.
- Responsible for making the grading rubric for each assignment in order to provide clarity on assignment requirements.
- Responsible for making the students more qualified for the next level of all courses.
- Helping Students in project week.
- Guiding new TAs and new Instructors through their journey in our program and that's due to my experience, new instructors will be supported and helped by the experienced TA.

Also, new TAs will be supported and tutoring to use Canvas, how to grade and how to deal with students so they will always be positive and fall in love with their coding journey at ASAC.

Al Hussein Technical University (HTU) NATIONAL ICT Upskilling Programme Internship July 2019 - September 2019 (3 months)

Amman Governorate, Jordan

COURSES:

- Technical (Front End Fundamentals):HTML 5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap.
- Soft Skills: presentation, interview, communication skills.
- English: Speaking, Listening, and Writing.

XPSBOX

Founder - E-Commerce Specialist October 2012 - June 2019 (6 years 9 months) Jordan

TASKS:

- Customer Services: receiving customers calls and requests over social media.
- Social Media: Manages facebook page posts and Advertising in daily basis.
- Logistics: Tracking customers orders with shipping company.

UNRWA

Computer Teacher June 2010 - October 2012 (2 years 5 months) Jarash, Jordan

TASKS:

- Computer instructor: create courses outline, create exams, manage Eduwave system.
- Monitoring School Lab: checking school computers, create eLearning classes.

Education

Jordan University of Science and Technology
Bachelor's degree, Computer and Information Systems Security/Information
Assurance